( DARK MUSIC )
( WIND WHISTLES )
( BOTH CHATTER INDISTINCTLY )
GIRL : Oh , this is a nice house , huh ?
- Hi ! ( CHUCKLES ) - BOY : Is that the daughter ?
GIRL : Where shall we park ?
- Uh , right here ? I don 't know . - GIRL : Right here ?
- Hi . - I 'm Sarah .
- Sarah , hi . I 'm Mia . - Hi , Sarah .
You spoke to me on the phone earlier .
- I 'll just give you a hug . - Hi .
- I 'm glad you 're here . Hi . - Gavin .
- This is Gavin and Luis . - BOY : What 's up ?
Do I look OK ? I gotta be all ... tucked in .
- LUIS : You look great . - MIA : Sorry .
I was gonna ask , do you want me a certain way or ...
Um , no . Just ... just be yourself . Almost , like , ignore these guys .
- Oh , really ? - Yeah , yeah , yeah .
- They 're invisible . - Yeah , that 'll be easy !
- ( CHUCKLES ) ' Ignore ' . - Wow !
Ma can come off kind of salty , but it 's all an act .
- OK . - She 's excited you 're here .
She 's been cleaning and dusting
like the president 's coming to dinner or something .
- ( WIND CHIMES TINKLE ) - SARAH : Ma ?
Well , she was back here . ( LAUGHS )
You have the grant money , right ? It said so on the flyers .
- Yes . - That 's what we 're counting on .
No , no , definitely . It 's part of the deal .
Roanoke will also help underwrite
some of the healthcare costs as well .
Oh , wow . I love Roanoke .
Yeah , it ... it has to be the right fit , though .
Of course .
- Please and thank you . - OK .
Kiss her ass .
- ( LAUGHS ) Smile . - Point noted .
I mean , I 'm sorry . You know all this .
- Hey , Ma ! - MAN : Yes , you did .
- MIA : Hello there ! - Oh , Harris is with her .
- WOMAN : Hi . Oh , gosh . - HARRIS : Oh , yeah .
- Those people are here . - Hey , Sarah .
- The crew I told you about . - Nice to meet you .
They 're here for the pre-interview . Remember , Ma ?
They wanna make a movie about me !
- Isn 't that right ? - MIA : Yes , hopefully .
- What do you think of that ? - I think it 's a good idea .
You do ? Well , we 'll see .
Oh , I 'm sorry . Yes , I 'm being a bad hostess , aren 't I ?
- Here . You take that . - MIA : Do you need ...
I 'm just gonna take this and put this stuff away
so that I have it where it belongs for next time .
Of course .
What is of interest is that this is of an educational nature .
That interests me .
Um ...
I 'm not interested in being exploited .
Oh ...
I 'm not the butt of anyone 's joke .
- Oh , no , no , no . - No , Mom .
Mrs. Logan , that is definitely not why we 'd be here .
You know , actually my grandfather had the disease
so it 's not just a grade for me .
- Oh , I 'm sorry . - Yeah .
Well
I am a very private person
and , um
I 'm just having second thoughts .
I think that you would be better off with someone else .
I 'm sorry . I know you 've driven a long way .
But I don 't think I 'm the candidate for you , so ...
Mom ?
MAN : What the fuck was that about your grandfather ?
I thought they were on vacation in New Zealand .
She just needed a little nudging .
MAN : I thought you said these people were broke .
MIA : She 's behind on the house , but she won 't sell ,
so Sarah 's in a tough spot .
( DOORBELL RINGS )
MIA : Guys , I want you to be on good behaviour , OK ?
'Cause she 's , like , a proper old lady .
So I don 't wanna be , like , hounding them .
- Hey ! - Hi .
- Hi . - Hi , Sarah .
- How 's it going ? - I 'm so glad you 're here .
Hello , hello . Welcome .
I didn 't know you guys were gonna come in , like , right away .
- Right , I know . - We wanna capture it all , so ...
I paint in here mostly now
because , you know , we don 't entertain .
- She 's an amazing artist . - No , it 's just a hobby .
- I 'm not an amazing artist . - You 're prolific . There 's a lot .
Oh , I used to know the name of this bird .
MAN : Looks like a blue-tailed finch , actually .
- Does it ? Do you know birds ? - Oh , oh , dude , no .
Well , maybe that is what it is . I don 't remember .
Oh , is this Bavarian crystal ?
DEBORAH : It 's better ... Yeah , it 's probably better not to ...
Yeah , we won 't be touching the old things .
You 're a curious guy , huh ? You wanna touch everything ?
GAVIN : Do you guys have a Starbucks in town ?
DEBORAH : Oh , no , no .
This is Sarah 's room . You can just take a look .
This was her room as a child . She loved cars .
We haven 't touched anything since she was a child .
I kinda like leaving it like this .
She was a big ball player .
I was never really allowed in here .
I guess you found your room . ( LAUGHS )
- Oh , this is us ? - There 's a blow-up mattress .
- I 'm sorry , this is a little ... - Yeah , this 'll blow up .
... a little more minimal , a little rustic .
( WHISPERS ) Say thank you to her . Thank you .
- Oh , no , it 's , uh ... - Say thank you .
- Thank you . - No , you have a different room .
- Oh , I didn 't know . - There 's no intermingling here .
Boys , stay there . And the door 's closed .
- Deborah ? - Yes ?
Thank you for your , um . . hospitality .
- Appreciate it . - We 're gonna have fun .
- Right ? - Yeah , man .
DEBORAH : OK , good .
- My Aunt Edna 's , um ... - This is amazing .
Urn ... What 's this ... Bedroom set !
- Careful with that , sweetheart . - I know .
Yeah , there . That one 's supposed to be there .
GAVIN : Were you ever in Germany ?
DEBORAH : No , I have not .
- Always been a regret of mine . - Mom , you went to Germany .
Remember ?
- Well , that must , um ... - Remember ?
Oh , must 've been a long time ago .
Well , but you were there . You loved it . Remember ?
The story of Alzheimer 's is never about one person .
My PhD thesis film posits that this insidious disease
not only destroys the patient ,
but has a physiological influence
on the primary caregiver .
Alzheimer 's occurs when abnormal protein fragments
accumulate in the hippocampus , killing neurons .
The disease then creeps towards the front of the brain ,
wiping out neurons responsible for logical thought
and problem solving .
It then assaults the sensory region ,
sparking terrifying hallucinations .
Eventually , it erases a person 's oldest and most precious memories .
In end stage , Alzheimer 's destroys the part of the brain
that regulates the heart and breathing .
When swallowing goes , death is not far behind .
- DEBORAH : Take this one off . - SARAH : Huh ?
- Well , it 's so military . - What do you think ?
Let 's just ... Yeah .
Wouldn 't you agree ? I mean , you always look so pretty .
Whatever . OK , fine . Yep .
- Thank you . That 's great . - Gone .
Happy ? - I am happy -
Awesome .
DEBORAH : Is that a shirt of your dad 's ?
I guess I would have , you know , a senior moment .
Sure , you know , I 'd put the toast in and it would pop up
and I 'd put the ... push it back down again or something .
Toast it twice . Big deal .
On several occasions , she left the stove on .
OK ? Burnt up the spice rack , the whole wall .
DEBORAH : If you remember your grandmother ,
she was frightening .
She would leave a pot on the stove
until it melted right down to the little glass top .
- Maybe it 's genetic . - So that was a clue .
I 'm just saying what was a clue .
Mia asked what 's a clue for me , and that was a clue .
Alright . That was a clue .
WOMAN : Deborah was exhibiting what we call MCI -
mild cognitive impairment .
Through a battery of tests ,
we were able to diagnose with 95 % certainty
that she was in the early stages of Alzheimer 's .
MIA : How did she take the news ?
It 's devastating , obviously , for anyone ,
but Deborah 's not someone to go down without a fight .
MIA : After the premature death of her husband , Dennis ,
to a pulmonary embolism ,
Deborah was forced to provide for two-year-old Sarah
on her own .
She leveraged their house as collateral and would go on
to start a highly successful switchboard answering service
for the town of Exuma .
DEBORAH : That was the way that professionals
received their messages
and , I guess , transferred information back in those days ,
was through a professional answering service .
SARAH : Everyone told her she was crazy at the time .
- Right ? - DEBORAH : They certainly did .
I was all alone with a small child .
SARAH : You can 't tell Mom not to do something
'cause then she will absolutely make sure she does it .
- I was the nexus of this town . - Yeah !
Doctors , lawyers , and Town Hall , everybody .
Three-martini lunches and affairs
and philanderers and alcoholics and ...
I had to cover for all of these people .
You didn 't have to . You chose to .
Well , I did or they wouldn 't have stayed with me .
- True . - I wouldn 't have had a business .
You know .
MIA : As the days pass , what becomes most apparent
is there are no small tasks for an Alzheimer 's patient .
- WOMAN : $ 27.96 . - DEBORAH : 27 ?
Let me see . Alright ...
OK , there 's some of the change .
- OK . - I just need the dollars .
Oh , right , OK .
MIA : Maintenance of daily living exacts a great toll
as organisational thinking is compromised .
It didn 't cook it all the way through .
I 'm just gonna put this here like this .
- Why , thank you . - Does it taste alright ?
- Is it sweet enough ? - Yeah , that is good .
Can you taste the vanilla in it ?
- That 's my secret . - MAN : She 's a fighter .
And she 's brave . She 's generous and kind .
But how do you fight your way through something you
you can 't see or know ?
I do all my little puzzles . I do crosswords .
I 'm lifting weights .
I am doing everything that I have read will help
to stave off the progression of this disease .
Stave it off !
There 's no cure .
And so when I am in the middle of something
and suddenly my mind just leaves the premises ,
there are no words to describe how distressing it is .
( WIND CHIMES TINKLE )
LUIS : Debbie in the garden .
Zoom in .
Slow push .
What is she ...
Luis , you 're supposed to be working on the edit !
- Why are you screwing around ? - I was just shooting some ...
I 'm hungry -
- You hungry ? - LUIS : Um ...
Let 's get some lunch .
LUIS : Mia , lunch ?
( STATIC HISSES )
( DOOR SLAMS )
( DOOR CREAKS )
Am I supposed to not talk ? Should I hold my breath ?
( PRETENDS TO CHOKE )
It doesn 't matter , anyway ,
because , wow , your blood pressure ...
- I mean ... - What ?
You know stress is the real killer , right ?
Don 't worry .
I plan on dying of cirrhosis of the liver , anyway , OK ?
- Right ? - Well ...
- Uh-huh ? - However you wanna go .
GAVIN : Whoa , put that down !
- Hey ! - LUIS : Put down the knife !
Hey , hey ! What , I didn 't take anything .
Look , whatever it is , I 'll help you find it .
I 'll help you ... Whoa , put that down !
- Hey , hey ! - ( YELLS INDISTINCTLY )
Get away from me ! Where is my spade ? !
- I didn 't take it . - You took it !
- Whoa , whoa , whoa ! - LUIS : Holy shit .
GAVIN : Tell her I didn 't take her damn spade !
DEBORAH : That 's where it was ! You took it !
GAVIN : OK , OK !
( POTS CLATTER LOUDLY )
DEBORAH : I need that spade !
- I need it ! - LUIS : Get down from there .
- They 're all in here . - I need that spade !
( SCREAMS )
Where here ? ! Where is it ? !
Goddammit ! GODDAMMIT !
My Spade !
MIA : Just check your rooms .
SARAH : Did you check all locked rooms ? You OK ?
No , I 'm not OK ! I 'm fucking far from OK .
- I 'm sorry . I hurt my back . - Here , take these keys .
Look , I don 't know , OK ?
Luis , I swear to God , if you don 't fucking get off my ass ...
You fucking look .
I 'm gonna go just see how she is .
GAVIN : Of course not .
( SOFT RUMBLING )
Wow , old school .
- MIA : Luis ? - LUIS : Yeah ?
- Is that it ? - Yeah , it was in the freezer .
It 's the only place she didn 't look .
Hey . Mom ?
Mom , we found your spade .
Maybe you wanna sit down , Mom ?
Ma , can you talk to me , please ?
Please , Mom , please .
- Mom ? - ( MUTTERS TO SELF )
- Mom , you 're scaring me . - ( TO SELF ) She knows .
( MUTTERS ) Sarah .
( MUTTERS INDISTINCTLY )
( SCREAMS )
- LUIS : Holy shit ! - Go get help .
- Oh , my God . Someone ... - ( STATIC HISSES )
Would you grab this ?
Should we put you in front or back ?
- In the front , I 'll sit . - In the front .
DEBORAH : I 'm ... I 'm just mortified .
I would never dream of speaking to anyone
the way I evidently spoke to you .
I 'm terribly sorry .
It 's ... it 's OK .
( CLEARS THROAT )
Oh , look at the leaves . Aren 't they beautiful .
Glorious time of year .
What do you mean ' home ' ? She 's got a home . What kind of home ?
You mean someplace she should go lay up in a bed ?
You know , under fluorescent light ?
Lay there all day , stinking like urine ?
That 's where you go to die , my friend .
That ain 't a place to live . This is a place to live .
- She loves this . - DEBORAH : That shirt .
Oh , that shirt I hate .
- Can 't you wear a nice blouse ? - I don 't have a blouse .
Nice to see you too , Ma .
- I missed you , yeah . - Nice to see you .
- Yes , dear . - Complimentary valet .
Oh , Harris , thank you for all your help .
- How 's your neck ? - It 's fine , it 's fine .
DEBORAH : Told you to stay away from here .
( DOOR CREAKS )
I didn 't know , I didn 't know , I didn 't know .
( CLOCK TICKS REPEATEDLY )
( BREATH ES HEAVILY )
( SOFTLY ) Please ... please ...
Stop ...
St-stop .
No .
( BREATH ES HEAVILY ) No .
MIA : Deborah 's brain is much like the switchboard
she so adeptly worked on for decades ...
Go away , go away
her misfiring synapses like the phone lines
being pulled from their jacks , losing connections .
As memories are taken one by one ,
it soon becomes clear that you can 't run from Alzheimer 's .
You can only face it head-on ,
hopefully with dignity and grace .
No , no .
It becomes clear that Sarah has found
her own coping mechanisms .
SARAH : I 've got no choice , babe .
She ... she 's not making it easy .
She doesn 't want my help , so ...
Well , I got the U-Haul from Monday , so ...
My girlfriend , Shelly , I could not tell her the truth .
I just told her I 'm moving back home for a couple of months .
I didn 't have the balls to tell her the truth .
You guys come have a drink , OK ?
It 's been a long time since I hung out , which is nice .
- It 's nice . - Really ?
MIA : Yeah , it 's good .
( CHUCKLES ) That 's funny .
LUIS : Why ? What 's funny about it ?
( LAUGHS ) It 's just weird .
It 's sweet , it 's sweet .
- ( LUIS SIGHS ) - You know , Ma , um ...
She sent me away to Richmond in ' 76 , boarding school .
- LUIS : Really ? - I was 10 .
She caught me out in the garage ...
We had , like , a little outboard out there for the winter .
And I was hiding out there
with little Annie Phelps , kissing .
We didn 't know what we were doing .
And then Mom ... Mom was so mad ,
she just got all red-faced and ...
She was embarrassed .
Yeah , whatever .
LUIS : To our fucked-up childhoods .
Yeah .
( BIRD CALLS IN THE DISTANCE )
SARAH : Oh , yeah , Saint Bernardine 's .
Hated those uniforms !
( HALF-LAUGHS ) Well , never was comfortable in a dress .
LUIS : Immaculate Conception here .
Oh , yeah ? Good Catholic boy , huh ?
Deb 'll love you .
( ELECTRICITY CRACKLES , DULL THUD )
- LUIS : What was that ? - I 'm gonna go check on Mom .
LUIS : OK .
( CHANDELIER TINKLES )
( INDISTINCT TV CHATTER )
LUIS : What ?
Hey . Deb ?
Deb ?
Hey , Sarah ?
( DOOR CREAKS )
LUIS : Deb ?
Are you OK ?
( TO SELF ) Standing in the dark . That 's awesome .
Deborah ?
( LIGHT CLICKS )
SARAH : Arts and crafts project at midnight , Mom ?
- LUIS : Jesus . - SARAH : Huh ?
She 's convinced there 's been an intruder .
Some ... some guy in the yard .
- ( LUIS HALF-LAUGHS ) - Yep .
No-one out there , Mom . Just the deer .
( LOCKS WINDOW ) See ?
She 's got those RadioShack motion thingies
all over the house .
Yep .
We 're nailing the windows shut again .
I 've learned not to argue with her .
( STATIC HISSES )
( FLY BUZZES )
( CREAKING )
( GASPS )
( EXHALES SHARPLY )
( CAMERA MOUNT MOTOR WHIRRS )
OK , I 've checked the upstairs bathroom .
I 've checked everywhere in here .
She was in bed . We went to bed . I had to pee .
I got up . I checked . She was not there .
- I 'm gonna check out here . - Alright , thank you , guys .
MIA : Deb ?
- SARAH : Mom ? - ( DOOR CLOSES )
SARAH : Mom ? !
Morn , I am not kidding you !
- Come on ! - LUIS : Oh , tetanus .
GAVIN : Uh , hey , Sarah ?
SARAH : Oh , fuck .
( DEBORAH GRUNTS REPEATEDLY )
- GAVIN : Oh , shit . - LUIS : Fuck .
( DEBORAH CONTINUES GRUNTING )
GAVIN : Deb ? Deb , what are you doing ? !
SARAH : Mom , come back .
- GAVIN : Hey , don 't touch her ! - Listen to me !
- Don 't touch her ! - OK !
- ( DEBORAH SCREAMS ) - GAVIN : Oh , my God ! Oh , my God !
- SARAH : Mom . - ( CONTINUES SCREAMING )
- LUIS : Back up ! Back up ! - SARAH : Please , calm ...
- LUIS : Give her room . - ( DEBORAH GRUNTS )
- ( DEBORAH WHINES ) - SARAH : OK , Mom .
( CONTINUES WHINING )
MIA : OK , Deb , you just tell me if this water is too hot .
How does that feel ?
Is that ...
Is that OK ?
( OMINOUS MUSIC )
Oh , you really gave us all quite a fright
with your late-night gardening .
Do you remember ?
You really don 't remember , huh ?
That 's OK ?
DEBORAH : My daughter doesn 't like manicures .
MIA : Sarah ?
OK .
She never cleans her nails .
Well , don 't worry .
We 're gonna clean up your nails , Deb ,
and they will be back to their perfect state soon .
Alright , so I downloaded some footage
before Deborah 's little ... night scamper into the garden , yeah ?
- Yeah . - About 2 : 58 , right ?
- Yeah ? - You 're gonna wanna see this .
MIA : What 's she doing ?
- GAVIN : Wait for it . - Is she asleep ?
Yeah , she 's asleep . OK , we 've seen her sleepwalk before .
GAVIN : Bam .
- ( DEBORAH WHEEZES ) - LUIS : Whoa . What 's the code ?
GAVIN : There 's no break in the timecode .
She must 've climbed a chair or something , right ?
- She grabbed a chair and just ... - A fucking chair ?
- There 's no chair in the shot . - Do you see a chair ?
( SIGHS )
MIA : See , yeah , that 's the weird thing ,
'cause the timecode , it 's like it 's one continuous ...
Right ? Is that right ? It 's one continuous ...
- LUIS : There 's no break there . - SARAH : It 's not ...
Because that 's impossible .
- Right ? - LUIS : Yeah .
This is not normal .
This is not a normal ... whatever you 're calling it ,
somnambulism , or sleepwalking .
I 've seen her do it before . It 's not this .
Nazir said she 's gonna up the Villaquil ,
so maybe that would help .
I have no idea . I hope so . God , I hope so .
MIA : Oh , there 's Harris .
You climbed up on the stove , right ?
You could 've hurt yourself , or set the place on fire again .
Do you remember that ?
DEBORAH : So I climbed up on the stove . Big deal .
Look , I 'm staying here . I 'm not gonna go rot ...
Listen to me ! Look at your hands . Look at your neck .
You 're a menace to yourself . Do you know that ?
- Go back to Richmond . - ( SCOFFS )
I know you miss your lady friend , anyway .
Go . That 's fine . I 'm fine here .
( FINGERS CLICK )
- ( DEBORAH HUMS TUNEFULLY ) - MIA : How 's that sound , Luis ?
LUIS : That 's great . That 's great .
- Can we ... - ( DEBORAH CONTINUES HUMMING )
- MIA : There you go . - There we go .
I 'm going to put a mic on you , OK ?
It 's called a ' lavalier ' .
I 'm just gonna put it on the , uh ... front here .
There we go . It 's a very nice shirt .
Very nice .
- MIA : Can you see the cable ? - GAVIN : I 'm on it . I 'm on it .
- That 's looking good . - OK .
How are you feeling ?
Well , I was feeling peculiar , but , uh ... not now .
Now I feel , um ... right as rain .
Deb , we have some footage we 'd like to show you .
Who is that , now ?
Is that me ? What am I doing ? That is obscene .
- Why didn 't you stop me ? - MIA : Uh ...
We tried to stop you , but you were in a fugue state .
You were hallucinating .
SARAH : Mom , it was really scary , OK ?
You were stabbing at the ground with your spade over and over ,
digging hole after hole .
That 's what you were doing .
Then when we got inside , you were sobbing , Mom .
MIA : Jesus , Sarah .
( DEBORAH SOBS SOFTLY )
- SARAH : Mom ? - DEBORAH : I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry .
SARAH : Mom , you kept telling me not to answer the phone ,
like he was calling you .
That 's what you said . Please talk to us .
MIA : Sarah , maybe we should stop .
( DEBORAH SCREAMS )
( ALL YELL AT ONCE )
SARAH : Mom , stop it ! No !
Morn , stop ! No , no ! No !
( EVERYONE YELLS AT ONCE )
GAVIN : Arggh !
- SARAH : Mom ? - MIA : Oh , God .
- MIA : You alright , Gavin ? - GAVIN : Am I alright ?
- Is she alright ? - DEBORAH : Sarah ?
SARAH : OK . Alright .
- DEBORAH : Sarah ? - SARAH : Yes , I 'm here , Mom .
What 's gonna happen is you 're gonna feel
a pinch and then a burn .
And I need you to not move when you feel that pinch , OK ?
Here we go . OK , here we go .
- ( DEBORAH MOANS IN PAIN ) - It 's almost over . OK .
OK , don 't move , don 't move .
- Don 't move . - WOMAN : Really good .
- ( MOANS AND SCREAMS ) - NAZIR : Yeah .
Don 't move . Don 't move , honey . Don 't move . Don 't move .
Don 't move . OK .
MIA : Over the next few weeks ,
the doctors run a number of tests on Deborah
in an attempt to explain the anomalies in her condition .
Despite the painful procedures ,
the examinations raise more questions than they answer .
A disturbing infection has occurred , resulting in
an inexplicable scaly quality to Deborah 's skin .
Has she been around any heavy metals ?
She does garden . You know , I don 't ...
We don 't have poison oak or poison ivy .
Do you use pesticides ?
Make the vertical line of the ' T'
with the white blocks , OK , Deb ?
Take your time .
- I can 't . - I just wanna see you ...
Whatever you can do , just try it , Deb .
- Can you do that ? - I tried .
- There . - You did ?
OK , you know what ? Can you show ...
Deb ? Deb ? Deb , don 't ! Stop doing that , Deb !
Deborah , stop , stop !
( DEBORAH GROWLS )
- Deborah , please ... - ( CONTINUES GROWLING )
Initially , we suspected contact dermatitis
or some type of allergic reaction to the medication
' cause this , uh ... condition
is not typically associated with Alzheimer 's .
Although , um ... when the immune system is compromised ,
sometimes co-infections can occur .
That 's why we 've , uh
we 're bringing in some specialists from Richmond .
( PIANO MUSIC PLAYS )
- LUIS : Is somebody already here ? - GAVIN : Yeah .
Fuckin ' hazards are on .
( INDISTINCT RADIO CHATTER )
GAVIN : Whoa .
- MIA : Sarah ? - GAVIN : Hello ?
- Deb ? - LUIS : Hello ?
- ( DEBORAH GROWLS ) - Hey , did you hear that ?
- What was that ? - It 's Deborah .
- ( DEBORAH GROWLS ) - LUIS : Who is it ?
- Hello ? - Just go in there .
( DEBORAH CONTINUES GROWLING )
LUIS : What 's going on ?
Get her legs !
( DEBORAH CONTINUES GROWLING )
( ALL TALK AT ONCE )
Gentle ! Be gentle with her !
GENTLE !
OK , come on , let 's go , let 's go , let 's go . Luis .
She was swallowing those things .
We have some scissors .
I don 't see why we have to do this .
Because you like to eat them .
I d ...
- Right ? - Oh , it 's silly .
Oh .
OK .
- ( SNAKE HISSES ) - LUIS : Oh !
Snakes .
Alright , Luis ... ( SNIFFS )
... I know you always said don 't mess with your equipment .
Where are you at right now ?
Fucking around with asps or serpents
or whatever you call ' em these days .
I 'm gonna take my Aunt Bonny 's cross
and I 'm gonna put it on the window .
That 's right .
What the ...
( WHISPERS ) This lady 's got issues .
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
GAVIN : Oh , hey .
- Letting all my heat out . - ( WINDOW THUMPS )
GAVIN : What ? What ?
( GAVIN BREATHES DEEPLY )
It 's a closed window . What is that ?
That is an open window , Mia .
GAVIN ON RECORDING : Oh , God .
Yeah , OK , so it 's open .
What ?
That could be anything , right ' ? A draught , whatever .
If you guys are scared of an old woman losing her mind , go on .
I want double my rate .
Double my fucking rate , or I leave .
- Oh , fuck . - I walk right now .
Fine .
- OK . Oh , hey . - LUIS : Whoa , whoa , whoa .
And if he gets it , I get it too .
( SIGHS )
Alright , you have sweet dreams now , OK ?
Hmm ?
OK .
( DOOR CREAKS )
( BIRDS CALL AND FROGS CROAK IN THE DISTANCE )
( STATIC HISSES )
( CAMERA MOUNT MOTOR WHIRRS )
( DEBORAH GASPS )
( PHONE RINGS LOUDLY )
- GAVIN : Ugh . - LUIS : What in the fuck ?
GAVIN : Damn , that 's loud . Whoa , whoa , whoa .
LUIS : I was having the best dream .
- ( PHONE CONTINUES RINGING ) - What is that noise ?
GAVIN : Oh , man , no , no , no , no , no .
- What , what , what ? - We 're bolo on the lights .
No , it 's not the phone .
( PHONE CONTINUES RINGING LOUDLY )
Hey , what is that ?
- I 'll get it . It 's , uh ... - MIA : Oh , my god .
Mom 's old switchboard system .
It hasn 't worked in years . Are you OK ?
I 'm gonna check on Mom . One second .
MIA : OK . Gav , where are you going ?
GAVIN : I don 't know . I 'm going downstairs to make a sandwich .
- ( PHONE CONTINUES RINGING ) - Oh , my God . Fuck .
SARAH : Mom 's not in her room !
- Mom ! Mom ! - LUIS : Deb ?
MIA : Do you think maybe she 's turned on
the switchboard or something ?
- LUIS : I don 't know . - SARAH : Shh ! Ma !
- MIA : Hey . - SARAH : Fuck .
- ( DOOR SLAMS SHUT ) - ( ALL EXCLAIM )
- LUIS : What the fuck ? ! - GAVIN : Whoa , whoa , whoa !
- MIA : What is ... - GAVIN : What ?
Fuck .
LUIS : What 's that scratch ?
- See that scratch ? What is that ? - MIA : Sounds like ...
LUIS : Think it 's coming from over there .
MIA : Oh , my God . What is it ?
You think she 's in there ?
Shh ! Shh , no .
What if it 's ...
LUIS : Just ...
( LUIS WHISPERS ) Easy , easy , easy , easy .
- ( METALLIC CLANG ) - MIA : Oh , my ...
Now it 's open to see .
LUIS : OK .
MIA : Can you see anything ?
No , no , no , no .
- ( DOOR CLOSES ) - MIA : Oh , my God , Sarah .
- Ma ? - ( DOOR CREAKS )
( WHISPERS ) That one .
That door is never open . You go in first .
- LUIS : What ? - Yeah .
You want the brown guy to go first ?
( LUIS MUTTERS INDISTINCTLY )
Fuck , fuck , fuck , fuck , fuck .
OK . OK , shh .
Oh , gross . What the fuck ?
This shit ain 't right . This shit ain 't right .
Oh , guys ? Guys ?
- SARAH : What ? - MIA : Oh , my God .
LUIS : Yeah .
What the fuck ?
Oh , my God .
( LUIS WHISPERS ) Whoa , whoa , whoa , whoa .
( MIA WHISPERS INDISTINCTLY )
( DEBORAH CRIES )
- MIA : Sarah ? - DEBORAH : Help me .
Mom , please . Mom ?
Oh , my God .
( DEEP VOICE GROWLS FROM DEBORAH ) Oh , you 're an ugly thing !
- LUIS : Jesus . - DEBORAH : You 're an ugly thing !
( DEBORAH BABBLES WITH A DEEP VOICE )
Arggh ! Arggh !
MIA : Shit .
( SARAH PANTS HEAVILY )
Someone call Dr. Nazir . One of you guys call Dr. Nazir .
( DRAMATIC MUSIC )
- NAZIR : OK . - SARAH : OK .
- OK , OK . - NAZIR : Calm down .
( DEBORAH PANTS HEAVILY )
SARAH : Mom , Mom , it 's OK .
- Mom . - DEBORAH : I 've just ...
SARAH : What ? OK .
- NAZIR : OK , just breathe . - SARAH : We 're good , we 're good .
NAZIR : Pupils are dilating . That 's good .
SARAH : Gonna get her water .
NAZIR : OK , we need to get her breathing under control .
SARAH : OK , OK .
NAZIR : Just ... OK , down .
( DEBORAH SOBS )
I know , Mom .
( EXHALES SLOWLY ) Breathe with me .
OK , breathe with me .
( EXHALES SLOWLY ) Shh .
( DEBORAH 'S BREATHING SLOWS DOWN )
- Yeah . - NAZIR : Her vitals are fine .
- Her brain is responsive . - OK .
All her motor functions are working . They 're all fine .
She really needs to rest now .
- OK . - OK ?
It 's a short-acting sedative , OK ?
OK .
It 's very safe ...
... if she has to be restrained .
SARAH : It was 337 . Over and over .
This one ? Ask her about it . Mention the number .
She 's trying to recall someone specific .
Help her single it out .
Someone like her especially ,
who 's stubborn and strong-willed ,
she 's not gonna let this go .
SARAH : And if I did this ,
if I encouraged this memory to come out ,
would she then have some peace ?
Remember when you asked me to pull
the sound off the camera from the switchboard ?
Yeah , well , I pulled the sound off and , um
and it was from the on board camera , so it wasn 't very good .
And there was some gibberish at the end .
Remember the gibberish at the end ?
Alright , well , I modulated the inflection .
It wasn 't like any acoustic range I 've ever heard before ,
so I brought it down , I sped it up , and
translated this shit online , dude .
Who is it ?
That 's your mom , and that 's French ,
saying some shit about snakes , " be my fifth " , or some shit .
Ma doesn 't speak French .
LUIS : Look , I 'm sorry , that 's French .
GAVIN : I got the fuckin ' transcripts .
I don 't care if she knows French or not .
I ain 't ever heard anything like that before in my life .
MIA : You sure this is the right file ...
- Yes , Mia , it 's the right f ... - SARAH : Turn it off .
Please , just fuckin turn it off .
Forward .
SARAH : Yeah , easy .
LUIS : Damn , how many attics you people got ?
SARAH : Her switchboard records are in here somewhere .
No , hold on , hold on .
Ah , bingo . That 's it .
There 's definitely something there . Can you feel it ?
It 's like ... it 's like jammed in ... it 's jamming it .
It 's right at the back . Wait , wait , wait .
Oh , yeah , I can feel it . I can feel it .
I can feel it . Wait . Wait .
SARAH : Careful .
- ( DRAW SQUEAKS ) - Oh , fuck .
Wait , there it is .
Yeah , this is the 1971 and 1972 index here .
Yeah , but there 's no customer profile . See ?
- Yeah . - That 's weird .
Mom was fastidious . Mom was like ...
This is ... There should be no holes .
Jack 337 , there 's nothing .
- 336 . - SARAH AND MIA : Yeah .
336 continued , and then ...
- 338 . - SARAH : Exactly .
GAVIN : What 's that ? What are you doing ?
The one page we need is the one that 's missing .
It 's been ripped out .
( CLOCK TICKS )
Sarah , does Deb keep charcoal in the house ?
Yeah .
- LUIS : Yeah ? - I mean , in her art room .
Hey , Mia , do you have a notebook , like notebook paper ?
There 's this little depression that 's right here .
Just line it up here .
OK . Here we go .
Oh , yeah .
- ( LUIS CHUCKLES ) - What ?
- LUIS : Here we go , here we go . - Is it working ?
GAVIN : This is some serious Scooby-Doo shit right here .
LUIS : Look how nice that is . ' 337 ' .
- SARAH : Are you kidding me ? - MIA : Yeah , great .
- LUIS : Here we go . - MIA : So smart .
GAVIN : I wouldn 't go that far . Oh , what is that ?
- GAVIN : Is that ' D ' ? - LUIS : D , E , J , A , R ...
GAVIN : DJ Raj ?
- SARAH : Desjardins . - MIA : Who is it ?
Huh !
" Local paediatrician thought to have killed some local girls . "
" Went missing in the early ' 70s . "
Yeah , I was young , but I still remember the curfews .
The whole state was looking for him .
LUIS : And she never once talked about this guy ?
No . I mean , he was infamous .
There was a whole documentary .
I can 't believe you guys haven 't heard ...
- Yeah ? - .. that name before .
REPORTER ON VIDEO : Still no arrests have been made
in the nightmare spree of killings
that have plagued the Exuma Valley for the last two years ,
leaving four young girls dead .
The teen girls were each found
with serpentine carvings on their foreheads .
Parts of their bodies had been cannibalised
and traces of rattlesnake venom were found in their blood .
Whoever performed the murders was re-enacting
a very specific Monacan blood ritual -
the cauterised symbol of the snake consuming itself .
The choice of the Monacan mines was no accident ,
built over a cave system sacred to the natives
which fed directly into the River Rouge .
Girls were sacrificed
during the times of their first menstruations -
'bleeding flowers as they were called .
The blood of their oestrus was offered to the demon
in exchange for immortality .
MAN : It 's only when the local paediatrician goes missing
that interest in the River Rouge case begins again .
Henri Desjardins is well known , he 's respected ,
he does a lot of pro bono work .
And a month after he goes missing
a local paperboy directs authorities to a house ,
claiming there 's a strange odour from the building .
The stench was the worst I have ever smelt .
I mean , guys were gagging .
Then we saw the snakes everywhere , hundreds of them ,
all kinds , just constrictors , rattlesnakes ...
Monacan totems , books on rituals .
INTERVIEWEE : Henri Desjardins had the ultimate motive .
He was dying . He had Lou Gehrig 's disease .
You understand how debilitating that disease is , don 't you ?
The Monacan ritual required five victims
to attain immortality and be free from the human body ,
yet only four victims appear .
I know he didn 't complete the ritual .
Maybe he had second thoughts . I don 't know .
MAN : Despite a massive manhunt spanning two borders ,
Desjardins is never seen again
and his whereabouts become the stuff of legend .
Some say that he fled back to Quebec ,
others that he ... he killed himself .
MIA : I got up this morning to make coffee
and she was on the stoop .
- ( SARAH MOUTHS SILENTLY ) - ( MIA WHISPERS )
( SARAH WHISPERS ) I 'm going to ask her .
( SARAH WHISPERS ) Yeah .
( SARAH STAMMERS )
Do you remember a man named , um
Henri Desjardins ?
He was , uh ... like , a local paediatrician around here
a long time ago .
That name ...
- ( CLEARS THROAT ) Yeah . - SARAH : Yeah ?
That name sounds familiar .
Was he , like , a client of yours or ...
Maybe ?
I don 't know .
I think so .
Well , he just went missing a while ago ,
over 30 years ago , so , you know ...
DEBORAH : He 's not missing .
He 's dead .
How do you know that , Mom ?
( HOARSELY ) Murdered .
Murdered ?
- Ma ? - ( MOANs )
- ( GROANS ) - M ... Ma ?
Sarah , it 's me . Do you need a hand ?
( RETCHING )
( BANG ! )
( DEBORAH HEAVES AND GROANS )
Stay with her . I 'm calling an ambulance .
- What 's going on ? - Stay with her !
- MIA : Luis , what is ... - ( DEBORAH WHIMPERS )
LUIS : Oh , my God . Deb ?
MIA : Oh , my God .
Oh , Deb ...
( DEVICE BEEPS REGULARLY )
MAN : Voice changes , self-alteration ,
feeling as if your body belongs to someone else -
all hallmarks of split personality disorder .
We 'll run a DDIS .
What about the skin ?
The biopsies came back negative for ichthyosis .
We 're still searching .
She puked fucking earthworms .
MAN : Your mother 's a gardener , right ? Your mom ?
You said she tried to swallow some objects before ?
You can 't be serious .
Well , she 's out back in the garden ,
she scoops up some soil ...
MAN 2 : Excuse me , sir ? Sir , you can 't be in here .
Come on . Come with us . You come with us .
LUIS : That 's her neighbour Harris .
( DEBORAH GROANS SOFTLY )
Obviously she did know him .
Desjardins was her client , Harris .
What ... Don 't try and bullshit . Why are you acting like ...
Nazir told us to !
She 's speaking French , obsessed with the guy .
He was her fucking client !
Fucker . Yeah , hang up .
We think Harris is being shady to ... I don 't know . Protect Deb .
But what if Harris is trying to protect himself ?
LUIS : It says he was brought in for questioning .
- GAVIN : Yeah , twice . - MIA : Look .
Here 's an article I found .
" Eyewitnesses say Sredl skulking around the Desjardins residence
" and scenes of the crime . "
SARAH : Well , I 'm stupid . What are you getting at ?
Well , AFTER Desjardins disappears .
GAVIN : Mia , come on .
MIA : What if Sredl for some reason -
he wants to save the girls or whatever -
he murders this Desjardins guy , right ,
and then Deborah , who 's his best friend in the whole world ,
has to cover for him and take the secret
and she buries it , like , so deep ,
it takes a disease to bring it to the surface ?
Oh , come on . It says he 's missing .
It doesn 't say anything about him being dead .
- LUIS : It 's so paper thin . - MIA : It 's not , though !
SARAH : I 'm ordering some dinner , OK ?
Yeah , why don 't you get on the phone and find somewhere ?
Somewhere with salad .
Oh , yeah , somewhere with salad .
In this booming metropolis ,
I 'm sure I 'll find a fucking salad emporium .
- ( BOOM ! ) - MEN : What was that ? !
- GAVIN : What was that ? - MIA : I think it came ...
- Did it come from out there ? - Yeah , it came from out there !
- What the fuck was that ? - ( BOOM ! )
- ( ALL EXCLAIM ) - SARAH : Somebody 's out there .
- There 's a man out there ! - MIA : Shut up !
Oh , my God , Sarah , he 's walking ...
SARAH : Hit the lights . Stay down !
- ( GUNSHOT ) - ( GLASS SHATTERS )
- ( CAR ALARM BLARES ) - MIA : Get away from the windows !
- SARAH : It 's Harris . - MIA : What ?
MIA : Gavin , I don 't have my phone !
GAVIN : I don 't know . He 's shooting up the fucking ...
- MIA : He shot out the window ! - Oh , God !
SARAH : Harris , what the fuck are you doing ? !
- MIA : Are you calling the cops ? ! - LUIS : That 's my mom 's minivan !
Yeah , I 'm at ... Yo , the address !
- ( GUNSHOT ) - I wanna report a shooting .
- SARAH : Calm down ! - He 's shooting a gun !
- What 's the address ? - 61 Pine Hollow .
- ( GUNSHOT ) - Pine Hollow !
- ( SIRENS BLARE ) - ( CAR DOORS THUD )
( BOTH CHATTER INDISTINCTLY )
WOMAN : Mr. Sredl will sleep it off in the tank .
Like I said , you 're more than welcome to press charges ...
You 're damn straight we wanna press charges .
Gavin , I told you I 'd fix your windows .
Y 'all can just let me know what you decide .
Luis , get that fucking camera out of my face .
- LUIS : Can we talk about this ? - No !
There 's nothing to talk about . I 'm fucking leaving .
You start projects like this and you just bounce in the middle ?
If it 's just about the window ...
It 's not about the window , OK ? !
That 's just fucking icing on top of the shitty fucking cake .
What about the switchboard , huh ?
What about the fucking window opening and closing ?
The bitch levitated onto a counter !
The Gavin train 's pulling out , bro . Last call , man .
LUIS : You need this pay cheque as much as I do .
Luis knows how to be a team player !
- Fuck both of you . - MIA : No . Gavin .
LUIS : Gavin , I 'm ... Hey !
- See you later , buddy ! - ( COMICAL CAR HORN TOOTS )
LUIS : God !
LUIS : Hey , Sarah ? You wanna grab some grub ?
Shit . Hey , Mia .
I 'm gonna get Nazir .
( PEOPLE CHATTER INDISTINCTLY )
OFFICER : I understand what you guys are going through ...
We just went to the canteen .
MAN : We ... we came back and her room was empty .
WOMAN : She was gone . I don 't understand why that woman ...
OFFICER : We don 't know .
We 've got the hospital on lockdown .
We believe she 's still in the building .
- MAN : She 's sick . - OFFICER : I know , I know .
We 're gonna find her , OK ? Guys , just calm down .
What are you doing to get our daughter back ?
WOMAN ON RADIO : Security , patient was seen
leading the girl to the abandoned wing ,
possibly the kitchen .
DR. NAZIR : Deborah ?
MAN : There 's no power here . Watch yourself .
- ( BANG ! ) - PEOPLE : Arggh !
DR. NAZIR : Deborah ?
SARAH : Why ? Why would she take her in here ?
- What is she ... - DR. NAZIR : I don 't know .
When we were moving your mom from Critical
she saw the girl and whispered something to her .
MAN : All clear over here .
- ( GIRL WHIMPERS ) - ( THUD )
- MAN : What was that ? - MAN 2 : Let 's go check it out .
MAN : Alright .
( INDISTINCT CHATTER ON RADIO )
- MAN : Goddamn interference . - MAN 2 : She 's not in there , man .
- We already checked . - MAN 2 : Now you tell me , fucker .
DR. NAZIR : Deb ?
Deborah ?
( MOUTHS )
Deborah , can you hear me ?
I need you to listen to me , OK ?
I know she 's your friend
and you can come visit her any time you want .
OK , Deborah ?
But you need to let go of her hand .
- ( RADIO BLIPS ) - ( NAZIR SPEAKS SOFTLY )
DR. NAZIR : She can come see you later , OK ?
Let 's go .
( SQUALLS AND MOANS )
- MAN : Get her down ! - ( SCREAMS )
MAN : Watch it . Get her arm !
WOMAN : I 'm trying !
( BABBLES )
- ( SOBS ) - ( SARAH CRIES ) What 's happening ?
- That 's my mom , OK ? - MAN : Hold her , hold her .
Oh ...
( GROANS AND GRUNTS )
- MAN : Alright , it 's in . - SARAH : Do something , please .
( SPEAKS HOARSELY )
SARAH : Thanks for meeting me out here .
I just
I just didn 't want to talk about this in there .
I can bless your mom with oils .
An exorcism is really
in the realm of science fiction , Sarah .
I ... I used to think that .
- I still do maybe , but ... - I know .
- But it 's not gonna hurt . - I know .
SARAH : We 've tried everything else .
- MAN : I understand . - No , you don 't know .
Sarah , it 's something that we just don 't do .
Yeah , you do . You have to know someone .
A mentor of yours . Someone . You 've gotta help me .
You need to accept this .
You really do .
There 's something else going on .
There is something else going on .
( DEBORAH WHEEZES )
MIA : What 's Harris doing here ?
SARAH : He 's been visiting the last couple of days .
Just give him some space .
I made contact with the anthropology professor
from the ' River Rouge ' doc .
I 'm Mia . I spoke with you on the phone .
Thank you so much for making some time for us .
- This is Sarah Logan . - Hi , Sarah .
Luis , my cameraman . I explained we 'll be doing some shooting ...
Right . Please , have a seat .
( DEBORAH SCREAMS AND MOANS ON RECORDING )
DEBORAH : I tried to wash you in the river ...
( DEBORAH SCREAMS AND YELLS )
The most logical explanation for all this ...
( SARAH SCOFFS )
... is that your mother has become obsessed
with the notable , public boogieman
to the extent that she believes she is Desjardins .
With all due respect , sir , this is more than that , OK ?
And that 's why we 're here ... for your help .
However , the notion of spiritual parasites
does exists among many thousands of cultures
in various incarnations -
the Masai , the Inuit , Aborigines .
The belief is that a weak mind is susceptible
to the invasion of vengeful entities seeking a host .
The young and the very old are most vulnerable ,
as well as the infirm .
Living among the Bantu , I saw a young mother
so overwrought by the loss of her son to typhoid ...
SARAH : Yeah ?
... that she held his wasting corpse for over a month .
LUIS AND MIA : Oh , my God .
DR. SCHIFFER : She fell into madness .
I tried to help her . She was beyond reason .
She took on the boy 's affectations ,
his personality , his voice .
She became him .
It took two months before the spell was broken .
SARAH : Broken how ?
A witchdoctor
a witchdoctor came
and burned the boy 's body ,
flesh to ash , purification by fire .
( DEBORAH WHEEZES SOFTLY )
( DEBORAH MOANS )
( METAL JINGLES )
DEBORAH : The door ...
Oh ...
We don 't have to do this .
No , no , Debbie ...
( DEBORAH WHISPERS ) Kill me .
( DEBORAH MOANS )
( MUFFLED YELLING )
( HARRIS GRUNTS )
HARRIS : Ugh !
( HORN HONKS )
LUIS : Well , this can 't be good .
SARAH : Luis , wait up ! Wait !
LUIS : Nazir said something happened to Harris .
WOMAN : Take it easy . Deep breath , deep breath .
OK , it 's alright , it 's alright . Nice and easy .
- SARAH : Oh , Dad ... - I 'm sorry , ma 'am ...
I 'm his daughter . I 'm his daughter .
- We 're prepping him for surgery . - I know . I appreciate that .
But , please , just one second . I 'm begging you .
- Bless your heart . Thank you . - WOMAN : Security !
Dad ? Yeah ?
- ( COUGHS ) - Where ?
MAN : Ma 'am , you can 't be in here !
- Harris , where ? Where ? - WOMAN : Get her out !
MAN : Please come with me right now !
WOMAN : Ma 'am , ma 'am , please leave !
- ( SARAH YELLS ) Harris , where ? ! - MAN : Come on , ma 'am .
You have to go outside .
SARAH : She buried him in the backyard .
- LUIS : Stop her , please ! - MIA : Where are you going ?
Then she got sick and he infected her .
- MIA : What are you looking for ? - This looks loose .
- LUIS : Desjardins . - MIA : Huh ? Whose idea was this ?
Was this Harris 's idea , Sarah , huh ?
- LUIS : This is insane . - Help me , OK ? !
- What ? - Please , Mia !
- Where ? Sarah , tell me where . - All around here . Just dig .
- Right here ? - Yes .
Guys , this is insane . We 're digging holes in the woods !
Either help us or shut the fuck up !
Sleepwalking outside , she was trying to find it - the remains .
Or HE was . He was inhabiting her . Shit .
- LUIS : The soil ... - SARAH : It 's different , right ?
- It is loose . - MIA : Is it really ?
SARAH : OK , thank you .
It could 've been rain , could 've been moisture ...
LUIS : Do we really think that there is a BODY here ?
MIA : You gotta let it go .
It was an old man saying some crazy stuff on a hospital bed .
I don 't think so , OK ? I don 't think so !
LUIS : I promise ... I promise you
we will look somewhere else in the morning .
- I 'll do it . - MIA : We 're four feet deep .
- There 's nothing . - But this is where he said !
We could 've started here . I don 't know .
- It could be anywhere here . - MIA : Exactly !
- We 're gonna be here all night . - I 'm sick of this .
- Fuck ! - There 's nothing here .
Wait . ( SHOVEL CLANKS )
LUIS : What was that ?
What ? No way . No way .
SARAH : Do you ... Oh , my God .
- LUIS : Are you kidding me ? - She got here first .
- LUIS : What ? - Who ? What ?
Oh , my God . Ma got here first .
SARAH : Look for fresh footprints , anything fresh .
Where would you hide it ? Where would you hide it ?
- SARAH : I don 't know . - LUIS : Nothing back there .
I can see through . There 's nothing here .
SARAH : The whole house , you guys .
MIA : Sarah ...
Do you understand what I 'm trying to say ? !
It was sometimes her , it was sometimes Desjardins
and ... and he 's making her keep it .
She 's got a cubby for everything . She 's a hoarder .
- She has a space for everything . - MIA : I 'm following you .
If we can find ... He inhabits her body .
She ... He had her dig it up .
MIA : Even if Desjardins had been buried in the garden ,
just think about it , OK ?
It 's been years . There would be nothing left !
- I mean , he 'd be decomposed ... - Back here , back here !
LUIS : OK , I got it , I got it .
MIA : Anything that was left of him would be ...
- SARAH : Fucking shit . Nothing . - LUIS : Nothing .
SARAH : Hey , guys .
MIA : What are you looking at ?
SARAH : I don 't know , but it hasn 't rained in a while .
It should not be wet . That looks fresh as hell .
( LADDER CREAKS AND BANGS )
LUIS : A third goddamn attic ?
- Are you OK ? - Yeah , I 'm OK .
I 'm so fucking sorry . Hello ?
MIA : Luis , you go first . You got the light .
- Fuck no ! - Come on , man .
We 've already been through this . You go first , OK ?
( LUIS MUTTER ) White people
and their basements and fucking attics .
Damn ! It fucking stinks up here .
- Oh , my God ... - MIA : Can you shine the ...
Hold on a second . Hold on .
Oh , my God . What is all this shit ?
You gotta see this .
What is that stuff ? Oh !
LUIS : No idea . Don 't touch that . Ugh !
( SARAH PANTS )
LUIS : Mia , Mia , Mia , Mia !
MIA : What ? What is that ?
What is it ?
- SARAH : I can 't ... - LUIS : Jesus .
MIA : Is it stuck ?
- Let me ... - ( GRUNTS )
- MIA : Ooh , Jesus ! - LUIS : Jesus !
- Oh , it ... Oh , my ... ( GAGS ) - LUIS : Oh , it fucking smells !
MIA : God , that smells fucking awful .
( SARAH GAGS )
MIA : Oh , my God . Oh , my God .
What is it ?
( MIA MOANS )
- Oh , God . Oh , God . - SARAH : Nmm ...
- ( GASPS ) Oh ! - ( MIA SCREAMS )
- LUIS : Oh ! - SARAH : It 's ...
- LUIS : What ? What ? What ? - MIA : What the hell did you see ?
What did you see ?
- LUIS : Oh ! - ( MIA SCREAMS ) Oh , fuck !
- SARAH : It 's him ! - MIA : Oh , my God .
LUIS : There 's a fucking body up here !
- ( MIA CRIES ) My God . - We have to , we have to !
MIA : I 'm not touching him .
- I will do it . I will . - I 'm not touching him .
I fucking can 't thank you enough , you guys . Oh , my God !
- Go , go , go , go ! - LUIS : Easy .
MIA : Oh , my God .
LUIS : What are we ... what are we doing with this ?
- What are we doing ? - MIA : I don 't ... ( GAGS )
- We 'll just put it here for now . - Oh , God .
- LUIS : Ugh ... - ( MIA CRIES ) What are we doing ?
We burn it , right ? Isn 't that what Dr. Schiffer said ?
- LUIS : Right here ? - Yes !
LUIS : This day just gets better and better .
- ( HISSING ) - Fucking dead bodies ...
( HISSING CONTINUES )
- LUIS : Did you hear that ? - SARAH : Shit .
MIA : It 's coming from inside here .
- What are doing ? - MIA : I don 't know .
- SARAH AND LUIS : Mia ... - Just wait , just wait .
LUIS : Don 't ...
- ( MIA SCREAMS ) - LUIS : Whoa ! Oh !
- SARAH : No ! - MIA : Oh , my God ! Oh , my God !
We gotta burn this . We gotta burn this !
- MIA : What ? ! Fuck ! - Please !
MIA : There 's one more here , there 's one more here ! ( SCREAMS )
Get it in ! Get it in there !
- SARAH : Fuck ! - MIA : Fuck ! ( SCREAMS )
Watch your feet , Luis ! Watch your feet !
- SARAH : OK , OK ... - MIA : Fuck !
- Oh ! - Sorry ! Back off .
- That is fucking impossible ! - You haven 't put enough on .
You haven 't put enough on . Oh , nothing , nothing !
SARAH : You have to push the thing !
- I 'm pushing it ! I 'm pushing it ! - No , you 're not !
- SARAH : Yes , yes . - LUIS : Is it going ? !
- SARAH : OK , OK . - LUIS : Yes !
- SARAH : Back , back . - LUIS : Burn , bitch . Burn .
Now let 's get the fuck out of here .
- ( UNEARTHLY SCREAMING ) - LUIS : What ...
- ( FIRE ALARM BELL RINGS ) - LUIS : Go , go , go , go !
SARAH : It didn 't burn . It didn 't burn !
- Something put it out ! - LUIS : What ?
( SCREAMS )
( ALL YELL FRANTICALLY )
MIA : Get away from the fucking house ! Run !
Oh !
- There was something in there . - LUIS : Are you OK ?
- Did you see it ? - I don 't know !
- ( MOBILE PHONE RINGS ) - LUIS : Oh , Jesus Christ .
- MIA : Hold on . What did you see ? - LUIS : Someone 's ringing .
- Wait , wait . Is that your phone ? - ( ALL PANT AND WHIMPER )
Hello . What ?
Oh ... What ? No .
- Oh , God . - LUIS : What ?
- She broke out of the hospital . - MIA : You can 't go back !
I 'm going back in . I 've gotta get him .
- LUIS : Sarah , please ! SARAH ! - Do something , do something !
SARAH : We have to take the remains with us .
She broke the restraints , OK ? She 's out .
- Fuck . - DR. NAZIR : Sarah , Sarah !
- What the fuck happened ? - Please don 't go in there .
- Don 't go in there ! - You can 't come in here .
- Ma 'am , stop ! - Get out of my way !
Oh , my God ...
- I 'm coming downstairs now . - What is that ?
A security guard downstairs is in anaphylactic shock .
- You have to stay here . - He 's being treated now .
- For what , Nazir ? For what ? ! - Snake venom !
( GROANS AND GURGLES )
( SNARLS )
( MAN SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY )
MAN : That is fucking bullshit !
You are not doing everything you can ! You keep saying that .
Everybody tells me they 're doing ...
- NURSE : Hey , calm down ! - OFFICER : We are , sir .
- We 're so sorry . - MAN : I wanna know !
- NURSE : We 'll find her . - I wanna know what happened !
- Where is my girl ? ! - OFFICER : We 're trying .
( SILENT AUDIO )
( MAN SCREAMS )
( SPITS )
( SIREN BLARES )
( BOTH SPEAK INDISTINCTLY )
We 've got a five-mile perimeter ...
We go back a long way . I 'm begging you .
- Of course we do . I ... - OK , OK , I 'm coming , right ?
SARAH : Well , he 's gotta complete the ritual ,
right , the fifth girl ?
There 's only one place he 'd go - the cave system .
He 's headed to Monacan Mountain .
She 's the fifth ? She 's gonna complete it all for him ?
That 's who he 's picked , right ?
MIA : I 'm gonna fill those syringes Nazir gave us .
SARAH : There 's the car . She 's walking .
OFFICER : Get in ! There 's a fire trail on the other side .
It gets us about halfway up . We need to get the jump on them .
- SHERIFF TWEED : Keep going . - OFFICER : Here we go !
TWEED : This is the fire trail
so it should get us up pretty close .
Requesting backup on River Rouge trailhead .
We 're heading north .
- LUIS : Whoa ! I see something . - OFFICER : There they are .
- LUIS : Oh , my God . - MIA : She 's got the girl .
OFFICER : Everybody , stay back .
MIA : Sheriff Tweed , Sheriff Tweed , I have this sedative .
If you can restrain her I can administer it .
Alright , stay behind me , but get ready .
- OK . - LUIS : OK , OK , OK .
- Mrs. Logan ? - SARAH : Linda , careful .
Can you hear me ? I just want you to know we 're here .
I don 't want to alarm you .
We 're here to help , OK ?
- Deb ? - ( WHISPERS ) Do you see this ?
Deb , can you hear me ' ? It 's ... it 's Linda .
- SARAH : Mom ? - LINDA : No sudden movements .
OFFICER : We need you to release the child , ma 'am .
LINDA : Deb , I need you to turn around for me real slow , OK ?
You alright , honey ?
Cara , are you OK ? Cara , are you hurt ?
Don 't hurt him .
- He 's a nice man . - LINDA : Alright , Deb ?
CARA : He 's gonna wash me in the river .
- LINDA : Deb , let 's ... - OFFICER : Jesus H. Christ .
LINDA : .. about getting you down this mountain , OK ?
No sudden movements from anybody .
Real still , Deb . We 're gonna do everything real slow here , OK ?
CARA : He 's gonna wash me in the river .
- Don 't hurt him . - Yeah , it 's alright , Deb .
- We got it . - CARA : He 's gonna wash me ...
Look at that . Everything 's OK .
Don 't hurt him . He 's a nice man .
Alright , you gotta be real still for me , nice and easy ...
- ( SPITS ) - Arggh !
- LINDA : Are you alright ? ! - SARAH : Ma , no !
- ( DEBORAH SNARLS ) - ( ALL YELL FRANTICALLY )
( OFFICER MOANS )
- Ow ! - Are you alright ?
- Get the girl , the girl ... - I 'm gonna get her , alright ?
- Come on . - No , you gotta get the girl .
I need somebody to get him down the mountain !
- LUIS : Is he alright ? - Oh , God ! It burns !
Take the sheriff 's car and get him down .
Luis , that 's gotta be you , man . That 's gotta be you .
- LUIS : Have you lost your mind ? - I 'm sorry .
I can 't ... I can 't leave Sarah . I can 't leave the girl .
LUIS : You haven 't learned shit . Take it . I 'm done .
- MIA : Be safe , Luis ! Be safe ! - SARAH : Mom !
LINDA : We need light over here !
- SARAH : Cara ! - Cara , honey , can you hear us ?
- Mom ! - Cara ?
SARAH : Can we move faster ? She 's taken her to the mill .
- We have to go . - LINDA : Get that light up here .
MIA : I 'm coming , I 'm coming . Cara ?
Shh ! Hear anything ? Quiet .
- ( WATER FLOWS ) - ( MIA SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY )
LINDA : I hear the river . Let 's move .
Sarah , hold up .
Mom !
LINDA : Hey , Mia , shine your light to the right .
- What 's that ? - ( RUSTLING )
MIA : Oh , my God . That 's ...
Is that the River Rouge from the documentary ?
( CREAKING )
- SARAH : What the fuck was that ? - Shh !
Mia , keep the light up .
( MOUTHS )
( LINDA WHISPERS ) There 's blood , footprints .
I know it 's your mom ,
But whatever this is , it 's not your mom .
- No , Tweedy ... - You stay here .
I 'm gonna bring her out , alright ?
- I 'm gonna bring her out . - Be careful , OK ?
( MIA WHIMPERS )
- Are you OK ? - Sarah , I lied .
In the beginning I lied . I lied about my grandfather .
I don 't give a shit . You 're here now .
LINDA IN DISTANCE : Cara ?
LINDA : Cara , honey ?
Cara , where are you ?
MIA : Can you see anything ?
( LINDA SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY IN DISTANCE )
- MIA : Do you see ... Arggh ! - ( GUNSHOT )
SARAH : Linda ? Linda ?
Linda ! Linda !
We 're here ! Linda ?
( MIA IN DISTANCE ) Sarah ?
Do you see anything ?
( TEARFULLY ) Linda , where are you ? Can you hear me ?
Come on .
- No ! - ( SCREAMING IN DISTANCE )
- No ! Mom ! - ( BANGING IN DISTANCE )
Mom !
Which way ? Which way ?
- MIA : Sarah , I 'm coming ! - SARAH : Mom !
MIA : Sarah ! I 'm following you ! Where are you ? !
Sarah ! Oh , my God . This is fucking ludicrous .
We 're never gonna be able to get out of here .
SARAH : Mia , calm down . I need you to keep calm .
We 're gonna get lost and we 're never gonna get out .
What ? What 's wrong with the light ?
SARAH : OK , Mia , I 'm gonna give you this ...
- MIA : Oh , my God . - OK ? Calm down .
- SARAH : You can do it . - Give me the camera !
MIA : Come on , come on , come on . Yes , yes , yes ! OK , got it .
- Sarah ? - ( CARA SCREAMS )
MIA : Sarah !
- ( CARA SCREAMS ) - ( SARAH GROANS )
MIA : I 'm coming ! Where are you ?
Don 't leave me , Sarah . Don 't leave me !
SARAH : Over here !
- ( MIA WEEPS ) - SARAH : They 're in there .
- ( CARA SCREAMS IN DISTANCE ) - Sarah , no , no !
( SCREAMING CONTINUES )
- She 's gonna die . Give me ! - No , no ...
Then I 'll go . Give me the fucking light .
Don 't touch anything . This shit will collapse .
- ( CARA SCREAMS ) - SARAH : Fuck , fuck !
- In there . - ( SNAKES HISS )
Ugh ! ( GRUNTS )
- ( SNAKES HISS LOUDLY ) - Ugh !
MIA : Here . Take the light . Here .
( SARAH PANTS )
- Oh , fuck . Go fuck yourself ! - ( SNAKE HISSES )
- OK . - ( MIA WHIMPERS ) Sarah ?
- SARAH : Just keep going . - MIA : I can 't do this !
Get ... get off of me !
SARAH : Shh , shh . It 's OK . Just stay near me .
OK , here 's what we 're gonna do . We 're gonna sedate her .
I 'm gonna jab her if I can get it in
and then she 'll be out , he 'll be weakened , right ?
- Right ? - ( CRYING ) Yeah , yeah .
Then we can burn the remains just like Schiffer said .
- It 'll be clone , alright ? - Oh , my God ...
You grab Cara , OK ?
Gather yourself .
We gotta shut this off .
She 's gonna ... she 's gonna see us .
- I don 't wanna do it . - I can do this .
SARAH : Thank you , thank you . OK .
( DEBORAH CHANTS INDISTINCTLY )
( SARAH WHISPERS ) Come on .
( DEBORAH CONTINUES CHANTING )
( SNARLS )
( CARA SCREAMS )
( DISTORTED SCREAMING AND MOANING )
( SNARLS )
SARAH : Get off , Ma !
( MIA SCREAMS )
- ( AUDIO WHINES ) - ( SARAH YELLS INDISTINCTLY )
( CRIES ) Holy shit ...
- SARAH : Are you OK ? Are you OK ? - Oh , my God .
SARAH : Come on . Cara ?
- Cara ? - MIA : What do we do ?
- ( CRYING IN DISTANCE ) - SARAH : Cara !
( CARA MOANS AND CRIES )
MIA : Cara ?
( SNARLING AND CRYING IN DISTANCE )
SARAH : Mom ?
( MIA GASPS )
( MIA WEEPS )
Mom ?
MIA : No , no , no ... ( CRIES )
- Oh , what 's that ? - ( CRACK )
SARAH : What 's that ?
Fuck ! It slipped .
- ( MIA WHIMPERS ) - SARAH : Shh . Shut up .
MIA : I don 't know , I don 't know , I don 't know ...
( SARAH WHISPERS ) Come on .
Come on .
( SOFT SQUELCHING AND CRUNCHING )
Come around here , OK ? Ma ?
- OK ... - No , Sarah . Don 't .
OK , OK , Ma . Here I come .
( MIA WEEPS )
Oh ... ( GASPS )
- Ohh ! - ( MIA GASPS AND WHIMPERS )
- ( GUNSHOT ) - ( CARA SCREAMS )
Wait ! No !
Morn , Mom ! Fight him , Mom !
- Fight him ! - ( ROARS )
- ( MIA SCREAMS AND SOBS ) - It 's Sarah !
It 's Sarah !
- Mom ! You can fight him ! - ( SCREAMS )
Fight him , Mom ! Fight him ! Fight him !
- ( MIA SOBS ) - DEBORAH : Sarah ...
MIA : Shoot him ! Shoot him !
Ma ...
( ROARS )
- ( WAILS ) - No , No ! Mom !
- ( SNARLS ) - ( SARAH GRUNTS )
( DEBORAH WAILS )
Cara , Cara , come here . Come on , come on .
- ( MOANS ) - Mia , come here .
Take Cara , OK ? Keep her behind you .
( UNEARTHLY LAUGHING )
OK , Ma , let 's get rid of this motherfucker
right now , you and me , OK ?
MIA : But we 've tried this before .
Not here , right , Ma ?
- Fuck . There it goes . - ( MIA SHRIEKS )
( GRUNTING AND SNARLING )
MIA : Arggh !
( RAGGED MOANING AND WAILING )
- MIA : Oh , shit ! - ( BOOM ! )
( DISJOINTED AUDIO )
- ( MIA COUGHS ) - Mom ?
Mom ?
- ( WEAKLY ) Sarah ... - Yeah ?
( DEBORAH WHIMPERS )
- Yeah , Ma ? - Sarah ...
Yeah , Ma .
( DEBORAH WEEPS )
SARAH : Oh , she 's burnt .
Jesus ...
Are you OK ?
( BOTH WEEP )
WOMAN ON TV : .. reportedly abducted Cara Minetti
from Exuma Hospital
and led local authorities on a grisly chase
cancer patient Cara Minetti is resting comfortably
at Exuma General tonight
after a harrowing kidnapping ordeal
that led to the death of a Monacan County sheriff
as well as numerous life-threatening injuries
to local law enforcement and hospital staff .
... outside the Exuma County Courthouse
where we 're just now finding out that Deborah Logan
was found medically unfit to stand trial
for the murder of Sheriff Linda Tweed .
Logan 's physical condition has deteriorated rapidly
in the months since the violent ordeal and child abduction ,
leaving her barely able to speak or communicate .
I 'm standing in front of the Minetti house .
This is the home of little 10-year-old Cara
who 's celebrating a special birthday today
and for good reason .
She 's in full remission from leukaemia
in what many are calling a miracle .
- MAN : Get it , get it ! Yay ! - WOMAN : Go , go , go , go ! Yay !
WOMAN : We 're celebrating her birthday and we 're moving on .
- She 's happy and ... - It 's a celebration .
MAN : You rather have this or hospital food ?
Oh , my God . You 're not giving her that huge piece .
I 'm tired of hospital food .
- ( HOOTS ) - ( ALL LAUGH AND CHEER )
REPORTER : What are you looking forward to doing
in your ripe old age ?
- I don 't know . - You don 't know ?
- No . - Well , you better make a plan .
I have one .
You do ? What is it ?
- It 's a secret . - Oh . Hah !
Well , thank you for letting us
come to your wonderful party , honey .
You 're welcome .
You 're looking at the healthy and happy face
of a remarkable 10-year-old girl .
It 's an unbelievable story with such a happy ending .